Now let's get into the actual description of this graph of this data.
现在让我们进入这个数据图表的实际描述。
Remember our goal is to help someone who's hypothetically on the phone in our meeting visualize what
请记住，我们的目标是帮助假设在我们会议中打电话的人想象什么
we are seeing.
我们看到了。
They can't see it.
他们看不到。
We can see it.
我们可以看到它。
We need to make it clear what it is we're seeing.
我们需要弄清楚我们所看到的是什么。
The first sentence just like our previous description class is is very important.
就像我们之前的描述类一样，第一句话非常重要。
Now we don't need to use so many adjectives because we want to be as clear and simple as possible but
现在我们不需要使用这么多形容词，因为我们希望尽可能清晰和简单，但是
we do need to very clearly state what the relationship is between the Y and the x axis.
我们确实需要非常清楚地说明 Y 轴和 x 轴之间的关系。
That's probably the most important.
这可能是最重要的。
Once we say that then we can go into some trends that we see and we can talk about the shapes the structure
一旦我们这么说，我们就可以进入一些我们看到的趋势，我们可以谈论结构的形状
of the points on the graph.
图上的点。
So let's let's look at it.
那么让我们来看看吧。
This graph shows the relationship between the total fertility rate or children per woman the total fertility
此图显示了总生育率或每名妇女的总生育率之间的关系
rate in countries around the world and the GDP per capita of those countries.
世界各国的增长率和这些国家的人均国内生产总值。
In 2004 there was a sharp drop in the fertility rate of poor countries between 0 and about five thousand
2004 年，贫穷国家的生育率急剧下降，在 0 到 5000 之间
dollars.
美元。
GDP per capita when the GDP is low the fertility rate tends to be high.
当人均GDP低时，生育率往往高。
In general wealthy countries tend to have fewer children per woman.
一般来说，富裕国家的每个妇女生育的孩子往往较少。
Or we could say have a lower fertility rate.
或者我们可以说生育率较低。
There are far more countries near the lower end of the graph in terms of GDP and relatively few at the
就 GDP 而言，接近图表低端的国家要多得多，而处于低端的国家相对较少。
higher end.
更高端。
We don't actually have to say that last part.
我们实际上不必说最后一部分。
We could leave it out because if there are the majority in the lower end then that means that there
我们可以把它排除在外，因为如果在低端有多数，那么这意味着有
aren't that many in the higher end.
高端的没那么多。
OK.
好的。
Remember there are a few over here in the wealthier countries and a lot of them over here.
请记住，在较富裕的国家，这里有一些，而这里有很多。
OK but sometimes it helps just to be extra clear to state exactly what you're seeing even if it might
好的，但有时更清楚地说明您所看到的内容会有所帮助，即使它可能
be a little redundant.
有点多余。
OK.
好的。
Let's just go through that one more time with a little bit more breakdown.
让我们再经历一次，再多细分一下。
The graph shows that means this is what I'm looking at.
该图显示这意味着这就是我正在查看的内容。
This is what it's telling me.
这就是它告诉我的。
We can't say tells we have to say shows shows.
我们不能说告诉我们必须说表演节目。
OK.
好的。
You could say I can see on the graph.
你可以说我可以在图表上看到。
But I think this is probably a better way.
但我认为这可能是一个更好的方法。
The graph shows keyword there.
该图显示那里的关键字。
The relationship.
关系。
That's the best word to use when we're talking about two things.
当我们谈论两件事时，这是最好的词。
You and me we're talking about the relationship between us.
你和我，我们正在谈论我们之间的关系。
We're talking about a Y in an X we're talking about the relationship between the Y and the X relationship
我们正在谈论 X 中的 Y 我们正在谈论 Y 和 X 关系之间的关系
means they have some connection to each other.
意味着他们彼此之间有某种联系。
Right.
正确的。
It suggests that they're not completely independent.
这表明它们并不完全独立。
That means if you change one you change the other.
这意味着如果你改变一个，你就会改变另一个。
That's what relationship means.
这就是关系的意思。
Doesn't just mean that I'm putting them on this graph it means hey there's something here a correlation
不仅意味着我将它们放在这张图上，还意味着嘿这里有一些相关性
that we can talk about we can discuss.
我们可以谈论我们可以讨论。
OK.
好的。
This graph shows the relationship between the total fertility rate.
这张图显示了总生育率之间的关系。
Now if you want to say the number of children per woman.
现在，如果您要说每个女人的孩子数量。
That's OK.
没关系。
You can say the number of children per woman.
你可以说每个女人的孩子数量。
If you're simplifying it but because you actually see fertility rate on the graph it's better to use
如果您要简化它，但因为您实际上在图表上看到生育率，最好使用
that term better to use what you see.
该术语更好地使用您所看到的。
OK.
好的。
If you want to clarify something though all you have to do is add or.
如果你想澄清一些事情，尽管你必须do 是加或。
And then say the other way to say it.
然后说另一种说法。
Total fertility rate or number of children born per woman in countries around the world.
世界各国的总生育率或每名妇女生育的孩子数。
OK.
好的。
We could say all countries around the world.
我们可以说世界上所有的国家。
But actually we don't know if it's all countries.
但实际上我们不知道是不是所有国家。
It probably is but it doesn't really say that.
它可能是，但它并没有真正这么说。
Does it and the GDP per capita of those countries.
它和那些国家的人均国内生产总值有关。
So that helps us make it clear that the relationship is between this and this.
因此，这有助于我们清楚地表明，这与这之间的关系。
We're not talking about different countries makes it very clear we use those to reference to talk about
我们不是在谈论不同的国家，这很清楚我们使用这些来参考来谈论
the previous countries that we said OK.
我们说好的以前的国家。
Then we just say the date in 2004 when did this data come out.
然后我们只说2004年这个数据是什么时候出来的。
Basically we don't know.
基本上我们不知道。
We don't know when exactly they did the study when they got the information.
当他们得到信息时，我们不知道他们究竟是什么时候做的研究。
But this comes out in 2004.
但这在 2004 年问世。
That's that's the year we have.
那就是我们拥有的那一年。
OK.
好的。
There is a sharp drop in the fertility rate of poor countries between 0 and about five thousand dollars.
贫穷国家的生育率急剧下降，在 0 到 5000 美元之间。
Because if you remember it's shaped like this.
因为如果你记得它的形状是这样的。
We need to help that person on the phone visualize this.
我们需要帮助电话中的那个人想象这一点。
If we say there is a gradual a gradual decline the feeling will be like this.
如果我们说有一个逐渐逐渐下降的感觉，就会是这样的。
If we say sharp decline that's still not so clear because it could be like that it could be like that
如果我们说急剧下降，那还不是很清楚，因为它可能是这样的，它可能是这样的
could be like that.
可能是这样。
So if we say numbers even if it's about we help clarify OK we can say around 5000.
因此，如果我们说数字，即使它是关于我们帮助澄清的，我们可以说大约 5000。
Between 0 and around five thousand or about five thousand GDP if we wanted to add the highest number
如果我们想添加最高数字，则在 0 到大约 5000 或大约 5000 GDP 之间
we could say the highest is around forty one thousand dollars.
我们可以说最高的是四万美元左右。
That's OK too.
那也没关系。
If we don't need to say that then we can leave it out.
如果我们不需要这么说，那么我们可以省略它。
We're still just trying to describe basically what we see here.
我们仍然只是试图基本上描述我们在这里看到的内容。
When the GDP is low.
GDP低的时候。
Now we're talking about this not quite analysis but we are talking about a specific trend that we can
现在我们谈论的不是完全的分析，而是我们可以谈论的特定趋势
see.
看。
We're talking about what happens when this thing happens when the GDP is low.
我们正在谈论当GDP低时发生这种情况时会发生什么。
The fertility rate tends to be high.
生育率往往很高。
That is a trend.
那是一种趋势。
So if there is a trend we often use the word tend to describe it.
因此，如果有一种趋势，我们经常使用倾向于这个词来描述它。
It is a trend that when the GDP is low the fertility rate is high it tends to be high.
一个趋势是，当 GDP 低时，生育率高时往往会高。
So don't be confused between trend and trend.
所以不要混淆趋势和趋势。
There used to usually talk about the same kind of thing tends to be high in general in general.
那里平时谈的同一种东西一般一般都偏高。
That helps us say well it's not always true.
这有助于我们说得好，这并不总是正确的。
Maybe I don't know but it seems to be true.
也许我不知道，但这似乎是真的。
It looks to me like when the country is wealthier when there's more money or the GDP is higher then
在我看来，当国家更富有时，有更多的钱或 GDP 更高
there are not that many children.
没有那么多孩子。
That's interesting.
那很有意思。
OK.
好的。
But we can use in general to say I'm not saying everyone is like this.
但我们可以笼统地说我不是说每个人都是这样的。
I'm just trying to communicate what I see here.
我只是想传达我在这里看到的内容。
In general wealthy countries tend to have fewer children per woman.
一般来说，富裕国家的每个妇女生育的孩子往往较少。
OK.
好的。
Or we could say fertility rate in general wealthy countries tend to have a lower fertility rate.
或者我们可以说，一般富裕国家的生育率往往较低。
Same thing.
一样。
There are former move but there are far more countries near the lower end of the graph.
有以前的举动，但在图表的下端附近有更多的国家。
So we could talk about the high end and the low end.
所以我们可以谈论高端和低端。
What does that mean exactly.
这究竟是什么意思。
Well usually when we say and we're talking about the x axis not the y axis usually usually and the low
好吧，通常当我们说的是 x 轴而不是 y 轴通常通常和低
end will be closer to zero.
end 将更接近于零。
The high end will be the higher number.
高端将是更高的数字。
That's very useful phrase the low end and the high end very useful.
这是非常有用的phrase低端和高端非常有用。
This is to help us talk about a maybe a spectrum member from here to here.
这是为了帮助我们从这里到这里谈论一个可能的频谱成员。
OK.
好的。
So there are far more countries near the low or lower end of the graph in terms of GDP.
因此，就 GDP 而言，接近图表低端或低端的国家要多得多。
Now in terms of is to help us clarify which exact thing we're talking about in terms of wealth in terms
现在，就财富而言，是为了帮助我们澄清我们在谈论财富方面的确切事物
of children per woman in terms of what.
每个女人的孩子在什么方面。
So if we want to clarify exactly what it is that is this way at the low end it's going to be GDP per
因此，如果我们想明确说明低端的这种方式是什么，它将是人均 GDP
capita in terms of you can use to talk about well this is my topic but in terms of wealth yeah maybe
就您而言，人均可以用来谈论好这是我的话题，但就财富而言，是的，也许 也许这个国家做得很好。
But in terms of equality not so well and in terms of nutrition.
但在平等和营养方面不太好。
Again not so well.
又不是那么好。
But in terms of the quality of entertainment then you can talk about whatever you want to talk about
但是就娱乐质量而言，您可以谈论任何您想谈论的话题
to say if something is good or bad in a specific place I love to visit for example I love to visit San
说某事在我喜欢去的特定地方是好是坏，例如我喜欢去圣
Francisco in terms of interesting things to do.
就有趣的事情而言，弗朗西斯科。
It's awesome.
这很棒。
But in terms of maybe cost it's not so awesome it's very expensive in terms of cost and relatively few
但就成本而言，它并不是那么棒，它在成本方面非常昂贵，而且相对较少
at the higher end.
在较高端。
So this is a very simple way to describe this graph.
所以这是描述这个图的一种非常简单的方法。
We could add more we could talk about the highest country being at around 41000 1000 GDP per capita.
我们可以添加更多，我们可以谈论最高的国家，人均 GDP 约为 41000 1000。
We could include that if we wanted to do that we would say simply the highest country or the country
我们可以包括，如果我们想这样做，我们会简单地说最高国家或国家
with the highest GDP per capita is at around forty one thousand dollars and the average children per
人均国内生产总值最高的在四万美元左右，平均每人
woman there is about two.
女人大约有两个。
OK.
好的。
So if we want to say that we certainly can.
所以如果我们想说我们当然可以。
Saying what's at the end might be useful in some cases so that it's clear what is the highest number.
在某些情况下，说出最后的内容可能很有用，以便清楚什么是最高数字。
Sometimes that can help.
有时这会有所帮助。
So I hope from this description you can pick out some of the useful phrases that we can use to talk
所以我希望你能从这个描述中挑选出一些我们可以用来交谈的有用短语
about graphs and always imagine that even if it's not the situation imagine that you're describing it
关于图表并总是想象即使不是这种情况也想象你正在描述它
to someone who can't see it that will force you to use very clear language.
给看不到它的人，这将迫使您使用非常清晰的语言。
And I think if we use this description and say it over the phone to somebody or for some reason someone
我想如果我们使用这个描述并通过电话对某人或出于某种原因说
is closing their eyes they can get a pretty good picture of what we're talking about if we use this
闭上眼睛，如果我们使用它，他们可以很好地了解我们正在谈论的内容
description they can get a good image in their mind.
描述他们可以在他们的脑海中得到一个好的形象。
What does this graph look like.
这个图表是什么样子的。
Next we're going to talk a little bit about how we might analyze this graph how we might break it down
接下来我们将讨论如何分析这个图表，我们如何分解它
break it down can say break.
打破它可以说打破。
Break it down remember analyze means to talk about maybe what it means even though it might be a guess.
分解它记住分析意味着谈论它可能意味着什么，即使它可能是一个猜测。
So let's let's see what that could look like.
所以让我们看看它会是什么样子。
Just for fun.
纯娱乐。